[
    {
        "question": "The quantity of money increases while real production remains unchanged. What result occurs?",
        "a": "unemployment",
        "b": "inflation",
        "c": "recession",
        "d": "deflation",
        "e": "liquidity",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following answer choices is the BEST definition of wealth?",
        "a": "stores of value",
        "b": "units of account",
        "c": "liquid assets",
        "d": "media of exchange",
        "e": "currency",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What PRIMARY advantage does cash offer?",
        "a": "convenience",
        "b": "low risk",
        "c": "return on investment",
        "d": "illiquidity",
        "e": "intrinsic value",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What function does a unit of account have?",
        "a": "It can provide valuable returns on investment.",
        "b": "It can be used as a relative measure of value.",
        "c": "It can be used to retain its worth into the future.",
        "d": "It can ensure all debts are paid.",
        "e": "It can be used to purchase other goods.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following stores of value is MOST effective?",
        "a": "stocks",
        "b": "currency",
        "c": "jewelry",
        "d": "cars",
        "e": "real estate",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following goods is LEAST liquid?",
        "a": "checking account",
        "b": "stocks",
        "c": "house",
        "d": "currency",
        "e": "savings account",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What prerequisite does fiat money require?",
        "a": "government power",
        "b": "currency exchange",
        "c": "neutrality of money",
        "d": "solvent banks",
        "e": "intrinsic value",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what MAIN way does fiat money differ from commodity money?",
        "a": "It is far less liquid.",
        "b": "It is not backed by the government.",
        "c": "It has no intrinsic value.",
        "d": "It is in much shorter supply.",
        "e": "It is less valuable.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What good served as commodity money in World War II prison camps?",
        "a": "gold",
        "b": "art pieces",
        "c": "cigarettes",
        "d": "bills",
        "e": "labor",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following assets is part of M1?",
        "a": "savings deposits",
        "b": "small denomination time deposits",
        "c": "demand deposits",
        "d": "retail money funds",
        "e": "credit cards",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why does the money stock NOT include credit cards?",
        "a": "Credit cards cannot be transferred to a new owner.",
        "b": "Credit cards do not store value.",
        "c": "Credit cards are susceptible to fraud.",
        "d": "Credit cards do not serve as a unit of account.",
        "e": "Credit cards have low market penetrance.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following features indicates that an asset is MOST liable to monetization?",
        "a": "government-backed",
        "b": "valued intrinsically",
        "c": "difficult to trade",
        "d": "in high supply",
        "e": "highly liquid",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are savings deposits categorized in the money supply?",
        "a": "financial assets",
        "b": "highest liquidity",
        "c": "M2",
        "d": "wealth",
        "e": "M1",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unlike diamonds, a dollar bill does NOT have",
        "a": "government regulation",
        "b": "stored value",
        "c": "liquidity",
        "d": "interest accrual",
        "e": "intrinsic value",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following ways does paper currency differ from a bond certificate?",
        "a": "It lacks intrinsic value.",
        "b": "It cannot be used to save money.",
        "c": "Bonds are not guaranteed.",
        "d": "It does not appreciate in value.",
        "e": "Less currency exists than bonds.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In monetary policy, which of the following values is represented by the equation M â€“ C?",
        "a": "excess reserves",
        "b": "real interest rate",
        "c": "reserve ratio",
        "d": "bank reserves",
        "e": "discount rate",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following situations would the discount rate apply?",
        "a": "bank loans to citizens",
        "b": "Federal Reserve loans to the government",
        "c": "bank loans to other banks",
        "d": "Federal Reserve loans to banks",
        "e": "Federal Reserve loans to citizens",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "What policy action does the Federal Reserve take LEAST often?",
        "a": "clearing checks",
        "b": "selling securities",
        "c": "changing the reserve ratio",
        "d": "buying treasury bonds",
        "e": "changing the discount rate",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "The government purchases bonds from the public. What actor made this decision?",
        "a": "Department of the Treasury",
        "b": "International Monetary Fund",
        "c": "Senate Finance Committee",
        "d": "Federal Reserve",
        "e": "Federal Open Market Committee",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Reserve increases the money supply if it",
        "a": "lowers the reserve ratio",
        "b": "purchases bonds",
        "c": "lowers the federal funds rate",
        "d": "lowers the discount rate",
        "e": "sells bonds",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following answer choices represents open market operations?",
        "a": "interest rate changes",
        "b": "currency issuance",
        "c": "exchange rate manipulation",
        "d": "stock selling",
        "e": "bond trading",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of bank is considered solvent?",
        "a": "Its reserves exceed its liabilities.",
        "b": "Its liabilities exceed its assets.",
        "c": "Its assets exceed its reserves.",
        "d": "Its reserves exceed its assets.",
        "e": "Its assets exceed its liabilities.",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following answer choices is most closely tied to the reserve ratio?",
        "a": "discount rate",
        "b": "federal funds rate",
        "c": "money multiplier",
        "d": "open market operations",
        "e": "real interest rate",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What DIRECT effect results from an increased monetary base?",
        "a": "Unemployment has decreased.",
        "b": "Inflation has increased.",
        "c": "People have more currency to spend.",
        "d": "Real GDP has increased.",
        "e": "The money supply has increased.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is another name for the monetary base?",
        "a": "high-powered money",
        "b": "solvent reserves",
        "c": "liquid assets",
        "d": "fractional reserves",
        "e": "illiquid money",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following actions will decrease the money supply?",
        "a": "decreasing the federal funds rate",
        "b": "buying bonds",
        "c": "increasing the reserve ratio",
        "d": "decreasing the tax rate",
        "e": "increasing the discount rate",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "What problem arises with fractional reserve banking?",
        "a": "lower money supply",
        "b": "higher interest rates",
        "c": "increased unemployment",
        "d": "higher inflation",
        "e": "lower liquidity",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE of the Federal Reserve?",
        "a": "It does not directly control the federal funds rate.",
        "b": "It most often influences the economy through the reserve ratio.",
        "c": "It was founded in 1918.",
        "d": "It is overseen by the President.",
        "e": "It consists of 13 regional banks.",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the reserve ratio is 10%, what is the money multiplier?",
        "a": "5",
        "b": "10",
        "c": "1",
        "d": "100",
        "e": "2",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following answer choices describes a role of the Federal Open Market Committee?",
        "a": "arbiter of imperfect competition",
        "b": "determinant of monetary policy",
        "c": "coordinator of bond purchases",
        "d": "manager of fiscal policy implementation",
        "e": "regulator of overall prices",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    }
]

